taxrates.com 2015-12-27

# Privacy Policy - Avalara

### Avalara Services  
Privacy Policy

Last Updated: April 8, 2015

This Policy explains how personal information of our business customers and prospective business customers is collected, used, and disclosed by Avalara and its subsidiaries and affiliated companies (“Avalara” or “We”). This privacy policy (“Policy”) applies to Avalara’s websites and mobile and software applications (collectively, “Services”) that post this Policy. This Policy does not apply to Avalara’s websites or apps that display or link to different privacy statements.

Our Services are not intended for consumers and this privacy policy does not apply to any household consumers. This privacy policy also does not apply to our handling of end user data we may receive from business customers who use our Services; Avalara handles that data as directed in our agreements with those customers.

#### INFORMATION COLLECTED

We may collect the following information about you when you use our Services. We may also combine information we collect about you with data we receive from third parties.

#### Mobile Apps.

When you use our mobile Services, we collect certain information that you provide which may be stored on your device and sent to our servers. Our Services may collect your geographic location such as your precise geographic location (e.g., certain of our mobile Services), the geographic locations you enter, and geographic areas derived from your IP address; information about your invoices including, for example, from and to postal addresses, invoice numbers, exemption certificate numbers; item descriptions, quantities, and amounts; and your contact information such as your name, email address, and company name.

When you use our Services, we also automatically collect information about your device and about your usage of and activity on our Services. For example, we collect your device’s operating system type, Internet Protocol (IP) address, device identifiers, browser type, device type, domain name, access times, duration of visit, platform, time stamp and other information. In regard to transactions conducted, we collect and transmit invoice elements required to correctly calculate tax information including the location of the seller, the location of the buyer, the date of the transaction, the product description, the quantity sold, and the total value of the transaction.

#### Websites.

When you use our website Services we may collect information you provide to us such your name, email address, phone number, fax number, VOIP address, postal address, billing and shipping information, company information, city and state location, credit card and other payment data, passwords, product registration information, product interest information, transaction information, and demographics. If you connect with Avalara accounts on third party social networking sites, we may also collect information about your social networking accounts, for example, your name, user name or handle, public profile, and email address.

We also may collect the personal information of people you refer and contacts you upload to facilitate the referral process, for example, if you provide email addresses of other people for email referrals or send us contact information of leads. We rely on you to obtain the permission of those other people to provide their personal information to us.

We may also automatically collect information related to the use of our websites – for example, we collect your computer’s operating system type and version, Internet Protocol (IP) address, access times, browser type and language, and the websites you visited before coming to our websites.

We may automatically collect information using “cookies.” Cookies are small text files stored on your device that includes a unique identifier. Among other things, cookies help us improve our Services and your experience. We use cookies to recognize if you have already registered, to understand usage of our Services and to enable us and others to track usage patterns and deliver customized content, marketing messages and advertising to you. We may collect information using Web beacons. Web beacons are electronic images that may be used in our Services or in our emails. We use Web beacons to deliver cookies, count visits, understand website usage and campaign effectiveness and to tell if an email has been opened and acted upon.

We and certain third parties, including analytics companies, advertisers and ad networks, may also automatically collect information about you through our Services, using cookies, Web beacons, and device identifiers, including personally identifiable information about your online activities over time and across different websites, devices, online channels and applications when you use our services.

#### USE OF INFORMATION WE COLLECT

We use information collected through our Services for purposes described in this Policy and as disclosed to you in connection with our Services. For example, we may use your information to:  
• operate and improve our internal operations, systems, products, and Services;  
• understand you and your preferences to enhance your experience;  
• respond to your comments and questions and provide customer service;  
• provide services and deliver products you request;  
• send you service-related information, including confirmations, invoices, technical notices, updates, security alerts, and support and administrative messages;  
• communicate with you and your referrals about promotions, upcoming events, and news about products and services offered by Avalara and our selected partners;  
• link or combine information about you with other personal information we get from third parties, to help understand your needs and provide you with better and more personalized service; and  
• protect, investigate, and deter against fraudulent, unauthorized, or illegal activity.

Avalara may store and process personal information in the United States and other countries in compliance with this Privacy Policy and applicable law.

#### SHARING OF PERSONALLY IDENTIFYING INFORMATION

#### Information You Share.

The Services may allow you to connect and share your actions, comments, content, and information publicly or with other people you specify. Some of these comments features are run by third party comment platforms. You may also connect to and share your information on third party social media platforms, websites, applications, and services through “plug-ins,” widgets, buttons, and other third party features on and connected with our Services. You may also share with Avalara contact information of people in your address book so that we can help you tell others about Avalara. Please be mindful of your own privacy needs and those of others as you choose whom to connect with, what you share with us and others, and what you make public. We cannot control the privacy of information you choose to make public or share with others. We also cannot control and are not responsible for any third party comment platforms, social media services or their actions including the data that they collect from you and your device or how they use such data. Please review their privacy policies to understand their privacy practices.

#### Information We Share.

We share your personally identifying information with third parties only for lawful purposes, including as follows:  
• with your consent, for example, when you agree to our sharing your personally identifying information with other third parties for their own marketing purposes subject to their separate privacy policies;  
• with third party vendors, consultants and other service providers who work for us and need access to your information to do that work and improve services they provide;  
• to (i) comply with laws or to respond to lawful requests and legal process; (ii) to protect the rights and property of Avalara our agents, customers, and others including to enforce our agreements, policies, and terms of use; or (iii) in an emergency to protect the personal safety of Avalara, its customers, or any person;  
• in connection with or during negotiation of any merger, financing, acquisition, bankruptcy, dissolution, transaction or proceeding involving sale, transfer, divestiture or disclosure of all or a portion of our business or assets to another company.

We may also share aggregated or deidentified information for any legal purpose.

### YOUR CHOICES AND CHANGES

You may opt out of receiving promotional emails from Avalara by following the instructions in those emails. If you opt out, we may still send you non-promotional emails, such as emails about your accounts or our ongoing business relations. You may also send requests about your contact preferences and changes to your information by emailing [customer.loyalty@avalara.com](mailto:customer.loyalty@avalara.com).

If you have an account with us, you may also change certain information you provide to us by going to your settings for that Service.

When you use our Services, you can usually choose to set your browser to remove cookies and to reject cookies from our servers. If you choose to remove cookies or reject cookies, this could affect certain features or services of our websites. Cookie management tools provided by your browser may not remove Flash cookies. To learn how to manage privacy and storage settings for Flash cookies click here:  
<http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager.html#117118> (or in the EU [YourOnlineChoices.com](http://www.youronlinechoices.com/)). You can also choose to opt-out of use of cookies by many of our third party advertising partners to deliver personally tailored ads by visiting the [Digital Advertising Alliance](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/) in the USA, [Digital Advertising Alliance of Canada](http://youradchoices.ca/) in Canada or the [European Digital Advertising Alliance](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/) in Europe. If you delete your cookies, use a different browser, or buy a new computer, you will need to renew your opt-out choices.  
While we and others give you certain choices, as further outlined in this Policy, there are many ways that Web browser signals and similar mechanisms can indicate your choice to disable tracking, and we may not be aware of nor honor every mechanism.

### CHANGES TO THIS POLICY

Avalara may change this Policy from time to time. If we make any changes to this Policy, we will change the “Last Updated” date above.

### QUESTIONS

If you have any questions about this Policy, please contact us at [legal@avalara.com](mailto:legal@avalara.com).
